(choir sings requiem)
(Bells jingle)
(Beeping)
(Whispers)
(Serbian) Mr Minister.
Someone paged me, but no one's there.
(Serbian) l paged you.
Yes?
it couldn't wait
until tomorrow at Parliament?
No.
(Speaks Russian)
Have our START friends given us
permission to do our job yet?
Yes, sir.
And we didn't even have to ask.
Something wrong, Sergeant?
l didn't join the Russian Army to
dismantle it for the Americans, sir.
None of us did... The world changes.
We must change with it.
(Beeping)
(Speaks Russian)
Everything is ready?
Everything is ready, General.
Good luck.
Thank you, sir.
(Whistle blows)
(Rumbling)
(Speaking Russian)
(Beeping)
(Russian) What are they doing?
(Brakes squeal)
(Russian) 8 minutes, 40 seconds.
No time to relax, boys.
0h, my God.
(Brakes squeal)
(Explosion)
(Speaks Russian)
0h, God. 0h, my God.
calm down.
We're going to die.
We're 15 km away. Under a mountain.
- l want my money.
- Be strong. You're an officer.
- I'm so afraid.
- No, no. it's time to be strong.
l don't think l am.
Pity.
(Gunshot)
Take him away.
(Beeping)
What happened?
l don't know, Dr kelly.
Please come with me, ma'am.
(chattering)
(Man) I've got estimates on
cloud size comin' through on six.
- What have we got?
- N0RAD's got R4 over sector 9877.
it's been localised.
60 degrees longitude, 50 lat.
- What about NPIC?
- Blast 40 minutes ago in the Urals.
Two trains collided. 0ne was
carrying warheads to cherbynsk.
Nice hair. Very au naturel.
Nuclear forces have gone to DEFc0N 3.
NMcc thinks Russia will use this to
veil troop movements into chechnya.
Not our problem.
Estimates from Livermore?
Five to seven hundred kilotons.
Mark Appleton's looking for you.
He's upstairs.
- All current data on my desk?
- Yes.
I'm gonna need a minute.
- Radiation pattern projections in?
- Yeah, but those aren't confirmed.
confirm them.
(Man) Russia, what a fucking mess.
l miss the cold War.
Get Essler down here now.
l need a translator.
Essler's gone. He quit to run JPL.
- Who did we appoint?
- My memo's on your desk.
- Who the hell's in charge there?
- Mark?
Mark? Excuse me.
Sorry. Forget chernobyl.
This is... This is huge.
Dr Julia kelly, Acting chair,
Nuclear Smuggling Group.
- Terry Hamilton, Security Advisor.
- We met last year.
I'm briefing the President to explain
how, with our START team there,
an accident like this could happen.
it wasn't an accident, sir.
I'm sorry?
We believe that train was carrying
SS18s, which are 0ne Point Safe.
- What's she saying?
- lf you fire a bullet at the warhead
there's a million-to-one
chance of it going off.
it must be ignited
by its own trigger.
Would you hold this, please?
Here we have the satellite imagery.
This is the two trains approaching,
and here's the collision.
Now check out the field of regard.
These shots are at the same height
cos they occurred at the same time.
Look. The blast is two degrees higher
after the satellites passed over.
Time between shots?
Between the train wreck
and the detonation, 4 minutes.
Somebody set that nuclear weapon off.
This was a terrorist act.
Full NSC briefing at 9:00am.
The Russians' accident story
will stand for now. No press leaks.
Nobody shows up on Nightline.
Doctor...?
kelly.
I'm putting your group on point
until l find a replacement.
Yes, sir.
Get me satellite overviews
and keep the updates coming.
0k, State, we're gonna need
talking points for the President.
We need to know who might want
to detonate a nuke on Russian soil.
General, I'll need a military liaison
with Russian contacts.
- You got it.
- 0h, and General,
make sure he's willing
to take orders from a woman.
'(Woman) colonel Devoe,
looking at events of May 18.'
You were arrested in a bar brawl
in a Moscow disco
called...Night crawler?
Yes, ma'am, that's correct.
You were in the company
of a prostitute
and a Russian army colonel named
Dimitri Vertikoff?
Yes, ma'am. Dimitri and l went into
the bar to try and buy some nerve gas
off this ex-KGB guy that we had heard
was selling black market
surplus munitions to Iraq.
The fight started because
we'd run up a bit of a bar tab...
l believe the exact
amount was $5,200?
Well, we had dinner,
and l bought a couple of rounds.
colonel Vertikoff
identified the KGB guy,
and we were able to stop
the nerve gas from getting to Iraq.
So how do you repay a man like that?
- Sports utility vehicle?
- That's exactly right.
Dimitri has a daughter
who likes four-wheeling.
l know this Ford guy who cut me
a great deal on these Explorers.
- l like the Bronco better...
- colonel, let's get this straight.
You spent taxpayers' money
to buy and ship
a Ford Explorer 8,000 miles
to the teenage daughter
of a Russian colonel?
Yes, ma'am.
Think of it as exporting goodwill.
(Russian) We never discussed
detonating a bomb.
lf they discovered missing warheads
they would have found us in hours.
Now it will be days before they even
reach the crash site.
l hate these new ones.
They don't seem real.
He looks bug-eyed, deformed.
They'll have the roads blocked.
Your Russian is awful. Speak English.
It was stupid, understand?
Your friends made this deal,
but this is my operation.
Don't make me start thinking
l don't need you.
- They will never let us through.
- 0f course they will.
Section 21-A,
Nuclear Disaster Protocol.
One, secure area.
Two, control debris.
Three, evacuate casualties.
(Speaks Russian)
Huh?
it was stupid.
(kelly) ..but they have the know-how
and should not be ruled out.
And moving on, we come to
Shamil Basayev, a scientist.
He claims responsibility for placing
a canister of radioactive caesium
in a park in Moscow last June.
But his underworld ties suggest he
could be part of a bigger operation.
Zelimkhan Yandarbiyev. chechen leader
since the Russians murdered Dudayev.
He has threatened to attack
Federation nuclear power plants.
There are others on our terrorist
list, as outlined in your packet.
0ur reaction to the crisis
is as follows.
We have initiated a directive with
the Nuclear Smuggling Group as hub.
DIA and NR0. You have responsibility
for primary SAT imagery...
Excuse me, ma'am.
l don't mean to interrupt.
- Yes?
- Um, these terrorists...
Have they asked for anything,
a list of demands?
Russians out of chechnya...?
No, but it's not unusual for days,
even weeks to go by
before a claim of responsibility
is made.
- Yeah.
- Air mob command is...
Excuse me again. Ma'am. I'm sorry.
That's a satellite shot of the
trains just before they collided.
Perhaps you should discuss
Special 0p possibilities?
Right. General Garnett has Special
0perations command at full alert.
- Excuse me.
- I'm sorry to keep interrupting.
You see these blobs right here?
Those are people jumping off
the train before it crashes.
Now look at that train.
That's the one with the nuke.
Nobody's jumpin' off that. Why not?
They were already dead.
(Man) How many warheads
were on the train?
The Russians haven't confirmed yet.
So we have no idea
of potential yield?
Are you suggesting
this was a robbery?
Whoever did this had access to
Russian satellite positioning intel.
That leaves out your chechen rebels.
(Murmuring)
l would like to point out
that 1,500 people
were killed last night.
You don't do that unless you want
to make a profound statement.
Do you know how much a nuke
is worth on the market?
Minimum $200 million, cash.
$200 million
is a very profound statement.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
The detonation was a smoke screen.
This was a hijacking,
and whoever stole these things
got off the bus a long way back.
(Murmuring)
Well, we will certainly be
considering your theory.
Thank you very much.
Well, it's just an opinion.
Whoever has current data on the
blast, l need it on my desk ASAP.
(Woman) You got it!
ken, try to get Russian Missile
command on the phone, please.
(Speaking Russian)
(TV) 'Reports say...'
- Anything on DIA?
- We should have Russian intel soon.
l need the START report.
Not just the summaries.
- Not just the abstracts, all of it.
- I'm all over it.
- And where is my military liaison?
- Right here.
Lieutenant colonel Tom Devoe,
reporting as ordered, ma'am.
My enthusiasm sometimes
gets the best of me.
l hope that l didn't
offend you in there.
No, of course not.
- coffee?
- I'd love some.
0ver there.
(ken) Russian Missile command's
on line six.
I'd like to reiterate our commitment
to helping you find some answers.
Yes.
- No, l understand, General.
- l brought you some coffee.
Uh, that's right.
We need to know
exactly who was on that train.
Uh, no, l am the man in charge.
l report directly to the President.
What do you want me to say?
l don't see what has to do
with anything.
Yes, well... l see.
No, l understand.
l think... l mean
l know l have a couple.
All right. lf you would
be able to get back to me
with the names of the men who were on
the train and the number of warheads,
- that would be wonderful.
- In my office.
And how long
do you think that will take?
Well, uh...
I'll be expecting your call.
Thank you.
(All talk at once)
(kelly) We got the confirmation.
-There were 10 warheads on the train.
-Forty men on board.
- This is meaningless.
- it's in Russian.
(Russian) it's meaningless because
they haven't listed anybody's rank.
Where did you learn to speak Russian?
Princeton.
The blue-blooded backbone
of our country.
- My father's a mailman.
- Well, you'd never know.
"Ilin, kodoroff, kulik,
Levindovsky..."
- kodoroff? Aleksander kodoroff?
- Yeah. You know him?
Yeah, l know him. God damn it!
l don't know about these other guys,
but General kodoroff doesn't ride
around on a nuclear transport train.
Get me NMCC lntel, please.
- it's like Ivana Trump on a subway.
- can you get my files?
- Have that enhanced off the Urals.
- Yes, sir.
Sergeant.
kodoroff's under investigation
for corruption,
probably gonna be indicted.
Gave a speech nine days ago
in St Petersburg.
Mostly nationalistic bluster,
bemoaning the loss of empire
and unity of the Slavic peoples.
Family history, phone records,
bank statements.
Urinalysis from a Moscow
traffic stop last month - .367.
- I'm amazed he could turn the key.
- That's a few cocktails.
Saw his dentist Tuesday, dined with
some attractive people on Friday.
- Haven't been able to ID them yet.
- costello, you're slipping(!)
- 0h, I'm gettin' old, sir.
- You're not old.
General Garnett's old.
If you don't mind me askin',
is kodoroff involved?
- We don't know. He was on the train.
- You see, that's funny.
Why?
The General's got a Finnish mistress.
- Lives in Helsinki.
- Laina.
The guy calls her every day
like clockwork.
- So?
- Well, the thing is,
if kodoroff was on
that train and he's so dead,
who's calling Laina in Helsinki off
some satellite over southern Russia?
lf that's a secure phone, l need it.
Excuse me, General.
lf a top-ranking
Russian general is involved,
any intel we get from Moscow
is either compromised...
Palkawunic Vertikoff.
- ..or a flat-out lie.
- You're right.
Dimitri, Tom Devoe.
- 'What do you want?'
- Are you busy?
I'm with two women.
call me back some other time.
- 'How are you guys holdin' up?'
- The only virtue is,
people are forgetting chechnya.
Yeah. Listen, I've got the
troop manifest from that train.
Alek kodoroff got vaporised
out there, did he?
- 'Yeah. What a shame.'
- Yeah.
So how is it he's calling Laina
from a bird over southern Russian?
How's he doin' that?
'Are you still there?'
'You must be wrong
about that, Tom.
'0ur figures indicate the fallout
should have dissipated by then.
'Let me fax you what we've got.
Your number?'
Hold on. Fax number, please. Hang on.
All right, 0-0-1-7-0-3...
- ..5-1-1-6-8.
- Six-eight.
I'm going to hang up now. Bye.
Listen...
That scared him.
- Is this the fax?
- Yes, sir.
(Newscaster) 'Information on the
nuclear weapon incident in Russia
'is still sketchy.
'But we do have facts about
the magnitude of the disaster.
'Seismographs around the world
detected the blast,
'and the explosion was seen
as far away as Lithuania
'on the Baltic Sea.
'Projections indicate the fallout
'will affect all of Russia
and northern Europe.
'There's still no word on casualties.
'President clinton will issue
a statement on this tragedy...'
Vienna, 2:00pm, Bacherplatz.
Why Vienna?
- kordech.
- Maybe.
kordech is a front for
the Russian Mafia in Vienna.
And it's a trucking company.
'Whether it was an accident or an
act of terrorism remains a question.'
l need N0RAD's sector 9877
intel from the Urals,
updated fallout patterns
and troop movements from NAT0 humint.
Honey-roasted. Think anybody'll
mind if l stole a couple of bags?
My old man will love
the Executive Seal.
Go ahead. knock yourself out.
Would you call Langley? We're waiting
for kodoroff's psych profile.
He's an asshole.
I'll save you a trip.
Thanks. I'll go with
the official version.
0k. 0fficially, he's an asshole.
He'll do anything for money,
which is good,
cos it makes him predictable.
I'd say he's been
anything but predictable.
He took an order for
an expensive, hard-to-find product,
and he intends to make good
on delivery - supply and demand.
Your area of expertise, colonel?
That's the word on the Hill.
You've been checkin' up on me.
l like to know who I'm working with.
I'd like to know something.
You moved from Lawrence Livermore
to the White House.
So, first you build the bombs
to blow up the entire world
and now you wanna save it.
Make up your mind, which is it?
Well, l believe this week
we're saving it.
- So, it's really that simple?
- it is to me, that simple.
When you've been the boss for more
than two weeks, you'll know that.
Three weeks.
You've done some checkin' yourself.
l like to know who I'm workin' with.
You can run your charts
and your theories all you want.
In the field, this is how it works.
The good guys, that's us,
chase the bad guys,
and they don't wear black hats.
They are, however, all alike.
They demand power and respect,
and they'll pay top dollar to get it.
And that is our
highly motivated buyer.
- What about other motivations?
- Not important to me.
Either way, there are people who
don't care about money or respect,
who believe killing
innocent people is justified.
For them it is about rage,
frustration, hatred.
They feel pain and want to share it.
That does me no good.
Let's deal with the facts at hand.
23 hours ago, General Aleksander
kodoroff stole ten nuclear warheads.
He's just a delivery boy.
I'm not afraid of the man who
wants ten nuclear weapons, colonel.
I'm terrified of the man
who only wants one.
(children chattering in Serbian)
(chattering in Serbian)
(Serbian) No, no, no. Listen, listen.
Music should be
like a language, child.
Listen.
Joy.
Sadness, you understand?
changing a single note can turn joy
to sorrow. Your turn.
(Phone rings)
Professor?
(Ringing continues)
- 'Hello?'
- Dusan? it's me, Vlado.
- 'Is everything 0k?'
- Yes, we're on schedule.
Brother, listen to me.
I'm scared.
(Devoe) Hey, look who's
the secret agent!
Nice hat. You don't stand out at all!
Dress shoes with khakis?
- Look at you.
- Leave me alone.
Listen, whatever happens, deny it.
0k. These are CDs for Tasha.
You will not like them.
How is she?
16, and in love with
a 20-year-old motorcross racer.
- She said to say hello.
- Send her my love.
Is kodoroff involved with kordech?
Dr Julia kelly,
colonel Dimitri Vertikoff.
Dr kelly heads
the Nuclear Smuggling Group.
- With the White House.
(Russian) A beautiful woman with
a PhD. You're out of your league.
(Russian) You have no idea, colonel.
That's good.
l think we can do business, Dr kelly.
- Let's take a walk.
- 0k, let's take a walk.
(Woman singing in German)
(Dimitri) They sit here and drink.
We might as well join them.
(kelly) We've monitored
kordech for years,
but it's always been
a Mafia/ex-kGB operation.
Till recently. You must see
it in the context of my country.
kodoroff's generation of officers
grew up in a crumbling system.
Those pictures
in your head of Russia,
bread lines, shitty little
apartments, ancient cars.
kodoroff and his friends made sure
that it never applied to them.
But now, even that system
is crumbling.
This was kodoroff's way out,
his big score.
So we're here because Y0U
can't investigate kordech?
No, l can't investigate
without alerting kodoroff.
Half the men used to be in my unit.
Mr Dietrich Shummaker schedules
all Russian shipping for kordech.
You have an appointment at 4:00.
(Devoe) Good, let's go
see a man about a truck.
That's gasoline!
- Do you have them?
- Yes. We have to begin immediately.
Just remember the plan.
- I'm Anthony Haden...
- I'm Patty carson.
We go in, we get the information.
then we get out.
You call me Tony. Here we go.
Hi, I'm Anthony Haden.
This is my associate, Patty carson.
- Herr Shummaker's expecting us.
- Please follow me.
(Receptionist)
'Make yourselves comfortable.'
Thank you.
Trucking business
must be pretty good.
l wonder what chateau in
the Loire Valley these came from.
Mr Haden? Welcome.
Thank you very much for seeing us.
This is my associate, Ms carson.
Nice place you have here.
My taste is for the Italians
but the German late Baroque
was influenced by the Italians.
Several of our paintings are Italian.
- That's a Tiepolo.
- 0h, yeah.
I'm a big Leroy Neiman fan.
Are you familiar with his work?
- No, I'm afraid not.
- No? 0h.
- Please, come in.
- Sure.
To my office.
- 0h, now, this is nice.
- Thank you.
Have a seat.
How can we help you?
l just wanted some information
about trucking in Russia.
l might not be the right man
if you need to rent equipment.
You're the head
of transportation, right?
The head?
- No, l just do the scheduling.
- Right.
You're the guy who gets things done.
Smart, put a German on it.
Yes, well.
As l said, how can l help you?
Well, what we wanna know is,
if l wanted to rent a vehicle to
steal and transport nuclear weapons
from somewhere, let's say,
inside the Urals,
would you be the guy to talk to?
Would you be that guy?
No, I'm afraid not.
l believe our meeting is over.
All right, thank you for...
- Do you like Ford Explorers?
- We have to go.
Range Rovers, Land cruisers?
Mr Haden, will you leave the room?
No!
Should've taken the money, Hans!
- Get up and get behind that desk.
- You broke my nose!
Not a word.
Get the tape out of my briefcase.
l won't shoot you unless l have to,
and I'll feel bad about it. Sit down!
Give me the tape.
- l need the password. What is it?
- Hang on.
- The password.
- No.
All right, hang on.
All right, Hans,
we'll do it your way.
How's the backhand? Password?
- Hasselhoff.
Hasselhoff...
How do you spell "Hasselhoff"?
Way to go, Hans. Very brave.
I'm in.
l need the trucking invoices
for the last seven days.
All right.
- This is your plan?
- Yep.
- This is your big plan?
- This is...my plan!
(Devoe) Hurry up.
- come on.
- Almost. Just logging off.
- Stay on. Who cares? Leave it on.
- Got it!
Good.
All right.
Thank you very much, Herr Shummaker!
(Speaks German)
- Go. Go!
- come on! come on!
- You get it?
- Got it.
- You all right?
- No, I'm not all right!
- Brilliant idea, smash his face in.
- That's how things get done.
A few bribes,
it never happened at all, right?
check the seats,
they go all the way back.
- 0h, yeah.
- cool.
- Embassy car.
- CD player, bullet-proof glass,
everything.
0h, shit!
We...may have a problem.
This will cost us. What do you have?
- Eighty.
- That's enough. I'll be back.
Hold this.
- So you think he set us up?
- Who?
- Your friend.
- No.
- How can you be so sure?
- Because he's my friend.
He needs more money. Give me...
(kelly) 0h, my God!
Out!
Get up front. Get up front!
Up front?
- They're behind us.
- How many of them?
Two...three.
Reach into that briefcase.
Pull out an extra magazine.
- Where is it?
- In the briefcase.
Damn it!
Seat belt.
(kelly screams)
come on, what's wrong with you?
What's wrong with you?!
What are you doing?
Shit!
(Shouting in German)
No! NO!
- come on.
- The invoices.
- come on!
- The invoices!
- come on, God damn it!
- No!
Go, go! GO!
Dimitri has a...
..a daughter, Tasha.
Sixteen. She lives in Rybinsk.
l remember when she was three.
She's... She's beautiful.
it doesn't make sense, you know?
You don't...kill a Dimitri Vertikoff.
There are certain rules.
killing him isn't useful.
Is it ever?
l never watched anybody die before.
(computer)
'Welcome. You've got mail.'
l e-mailed Shummaker's files to
my A0L account before l logged off.
Did it work?
Uh...yeah.
We're looking for a vehicle hired
in the Urals on about June 29.
Right?
- The truck's too small.
- Yes. St Petersburg, one direction.
Point of origin, chelyabinsk.
Registration number, 7056BM.
Destination, Imisli 44E.
That's Azerbaijan.
it's just south of Russia.
Five miles from fuckin' Iran!
He crosses that border
and those nukes are gone!
We got a bank-routing code number.
There's no client names. "44E",
does that mean anything to you?
- What?
- Shummaker put a private memo
on the invoice. it can't be copied.
This is Devoe, we have a target
vehicle. it's a cargo truck.
Registration 7056 Bravo Mike.
it's travelling south from
chelyabinsk to Imisli in Azerbaijan.
l am requesting
a high-priority tasker.
Any birds...
Any birds find this truck.
We've got nukes heading for Iran.
What the hell is 44E?
(Arguing in Serbian)
(Serbian) Gentlemen, please.
Zarko Preljevik has died.
He never regained consciousness
after being shot outside his church.
His death is a tragic loss
to his family, to his country,
to our hopes of peace.
(Murmuring)
We know you've
avoided politics, Dusan,
but you are the alternate.
Your people need you.
l am a Serb. I'm a croat.
I'm a Muslim.
You will look at what
l have done and say,
"0f course. Why not?
They are all animals."
They have slaughtered
each other for centuries.
But the truth is,
l am not a monster.
I'm a human man.
I'm just like you,
whether you like it or not.
(Soldiers chattering)
(Man) Hey, Rich, how you doing?
We haven't seen you
since the great scud hunt!
- captain Santiago, sir.
- Hello, captain.
This is Lieutenant Beach. He'll
run the operation from the ground.
- Gentlemen, have you found him?
- Damn close, sir.
Giving them an
average speed of 65 clicks,
if their destination is Imisli
and they take a direct route,
we put them about here, in Dagestan.
Still in Russia,
below Makhackala on the caspian Sea.
We've looked at everything
within a 200-square-mile area.
We haven't found the truck.
They're probably stuck here, in kuma.
There's a hell
of a traffic jam down there.
Trucks are too close together.
We can't get an angle on the plates.
- What's going on down there?
- Armenia and Azerbaijan fighting.
Roads are clogged
with refugees fleeing north.
ken? Get me a copy of kodoroff's
intel phone records.
- What are you thinking?
- l need an outside line.
Somebody give me
an outside line, please?
(Horn)
Filthy fucking refugees.
Azerbaijani, Georgian, kazhakstani.
Don't curse them.
l don't care what bitch gave
birth to them, Muslim, Serb.
l don't hate them for who they are.
l hate them because they are poor.
(Phone rings)
(Speaks Russian)
- 'Alek, how's the ride down there?'
- Who is this?
Doesn't traffic drive you nuts?
- Who the fuck is this?
- 'it's Tom Devoe. How you been?'
You still humpin' that
Finnish stewardess with the bad skin?
Tom. Are you still trading
stolen cars on the black market?
Hey, Alek, you watched CNN
during Desert Storm.
Remember those shots from
the nose of the missiles
slammin' into those trucks?
'Remember that picture?
'How it kept gettin' closer
and bigger on the screen?'
You could just about see the faces
of those drivers, and then...
Zap, the picture went dead.
We didn't see what happened next.
Well, guess what, Alek?
You will, you son of a bitch.
Shit. Get out of the way!
- l guess that upset him.
- can you get an angle?
He rear-ends some guy,
can it detonate that nuke?
As long as no one opens the primary,
it's 0k.
come on, sweetie. come on.
It's coming.
70-56 Bravo Mike. That's it.
How long until
the satellite's out of range?
- 0ne hour, 46 minutes.
- contact Russian command.
Give them the location of the truck.
Boom!
(kelly) We only have them under
surveillance for another hour.
(Devoe) it doesn't matter what
the State Department says.
(kelly) No, l understand, sir.
(Both) Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
- Ok, go. You go.
- No, you go first.
l talked to the chairman
of the Joint chiefs.
- Department's draggin' their feet.
- l was talking to the President.
He says the Russians
have to manage it.
No, we have the advantage!
The Russians say
they are handling this.
The Russians couldn't find snow
in the middle of fuckin' winter.
When that satellite is out of range,
those nukes are gone.
it's only jet fuel.
- Get up into NAT0.
- Good for you. Let's go. Rich?
No, wait. Wait, colonel.
With Russia determined to handle this
take no action without authorisation.
Do you think I'm some
stupid son of a bitch?
No, l don't think you're stupid.
You're a talented soldier
with bad impulse control.
l don't want
an international incident
- because of a personal agenda.
- My personal agenda is my business.
Now you are not in Washington.
You are in the real world,
and there are nuclear arms
heading for Iran.
So whether you agree with me
or not, get me authorised!
(Serbian) We must go, Dusan.
cobra Three, this is Tango Six.
What have we got?
(kelly) 'Russian command has been
notified of target's location.
'Proceed and await instructions.'
- Does NR0 have anything for us?
- They got us on standby.
How much time are we looking at?
We can track'em for 45 minutes.
We'll alert lF0R at Bazta checkpoint.
They have to pass through there.
Put that away.
(Russian) Step out
of the truck, please.
I'm sorry, General.
We've been ordered
to check all vehicles.
We're just carrying medical supplies.
Let us through.
I'm sorry sir, but l have orders.
Look at your code book, Sergeant.
Today's authorisation code
is... X16...7kTR...B
Yes, but l still have
to search the truck.
What is your name and unit?
Name and unit, you hear me?
- I'm sorry, General. Go ahead.
- Thank you, Sergeant.
Stop.
I'm sorry, sir, you'll have
to get out of the truck.
Get out of the truck immediately!
0f course.
(Reporter) 'There's been a setback
in the ongoing effort
'to secure peace
in the former Yugoslavia.
'So far, no one has taken
responsibility
'for the killing of the Bosnian-Serb
minister, Zarko Preljevik,
'who was assassinated
in a Sarajevo churchyard.
'Word of his death sent shock waves
through the international community.
'He was considered a crucial player
'in the peace talks scheduled
to begin this week in New York.
'Reporting live from Sarajevo,
this is Jean Rogers for CNN.'
Forty-four E.
Forty-fourth parallel
runs through...
Sarajevo.
Where's that bank number?
The one off the kordech invoice?
- check it against banks in Sarajevo.
- Doctor?
- What's going on?
- A Russian roadblock.
They're all dead, ma'am.
l think they're all dead.
(Devoe) 'cobra Three, they got 'em?'
Negative. How much longer
do we have them on satellite?
Less than 10 minutes.
Alert the Russians of the truck's
position and that they have men down.
Stand by to track.
(Devoe)
'We've reached Federation airspace.'
Running out of time, suggest we go.
Negative. Do not proceed
without authorisation.
- Any Russians troops in the area?
- Negative.
(Devoe) 'We're gonna lose'em.
We have to go.'
Get me a secure link
to NMcc. Negative, Six.
Do not proceed without authorisation.
You will not proceed.
When we lose the satellite,
do we have other eyes?
(kelly) 'Sir, target vehicle
is approaching lranian border.'
Requesting permission to enter
Russian airspace and take it out.
ln your estimation, is this
our only course of action?
Based on available intel,
no Russian forces in place,
our analysis of the satellite...
'I'm not asking for analysis,
I'm asking for a decision.'
Must advise we go, sir.
Dr kelly, if there are
nuclear weapons on that truck
and the Russians can't interdict,
are you willing to risk a war
to stop it?
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir, l am.
'Six, this is cobra Three.
We have a go.'
Avoid casualties. Secure the target
vehicle. Detain anyone inside.
copy. Six to task force.
We're cleared. Let's rock and roll!
'This is Red Dog Pack to Three.
Execute. Execute.'
Why aren't they finished back there?
(Speaking Russian)
(conversation in Russian)
Unidentified aircraft, you have
entered Russian airspace.
identify yourself immediately.
commander...
Russian control tower,
this is Air Force 53762.
'A flight of three
US Air force helicopters
'in pursuit of stolen
nuclear weapons.
'Request a weapons-hold status.'
Three American Air Force helicopters.
Low altitude, approximately
175 kilometres per hour.
Requesting weapons-hold status.
Intrusion section 187.
Activate tracking
and firing sequence.
All batteries... 0n my command.
You must return
to Turkish airspace, US Air Force.
'Your intrusion is not authorised.
You have crossed international line.'
Battery one tracking.
They've locked on to us.
Battery two tracking.
A second battery's locked on to us.
Get Southern command on the line.
Tell them we have unauthorised entry.
'This is Air Force 53762.'
'We are in pursuit of stolen nuclear
weapons on their way to Iran.'
Repeat. Put your weapons on hold.
Batteries tracking. Ready to fire.
Reverse course immediately,
or we will begin to fire.
This is Red Dog 3.
We're lit up like a christmas tree.
'This is Air Force 53762.'
Those weapons could be going
to chechnya or Georgia.
We repeat. Put your weapons on hold.
- They haven't answered yet.
- We'll lose track in 8 seconds.
Take them out.
Here they come!
(Devoe) 'Number 0ne is down.'
'We have a downed aircraft
two miles east of checkpoint four.'
- Number Three, acknowledge.
- This is Red Dog Three.
'Do you see the aircraft
or any survivors?'
Negative.
The whole forest is up in flames.
Number Three, duck behind the hill.
Behind the hill!
- How many men on that chopper?
- Nine.
(Devoe)
'cobra Three, we're out of range.
'Target is two miles out.'
Here it is.
What's he doing?
- Will it work?
- it can be activated by one man.
it will render a nuclear yield
of two kilotons.
- Why is he doing that now?
- Because that was the deal.
0ne warhead for us,
to do with as we wish.
After l get my money.
Helicopters!
Whatever you do, do not shoot
any civilians. Do you understand?
Amerikanze.
Take out the road.
Rig me a heavy lift line.
Those fuckers you can shoot.
Let's get him out! Pull up!
Where are they goin', Alek?
Where are they goin'?
Fuck you.
Get it down. Lower it.
Heavy line! Let's go!
- Grab it and get out!
- Drop a cable!
Bring it down. More! More!
come on, get on! Hook on!
- More!
- Lower it! We gotta lower it!
Aaaagh!
Go!
We're clear!
All right, sweep 'em. 0pen 'em up.
Let's go. Let's go.
- You all right, sir?
- Yeah. 0pen'em up. Let's go.
(Devoe) Give me a radio.
cobra Three, are you there?
Six, what happened?
0ne assault aircraft is gone.
Nine men are dead.
kodoroff is dead,
and we have recovered
eight nuclear warheads
- in their containers.
- That's not enough.
- What?
- 'That's not enough damn warheads.'
- For once, say something nice.
- it was an SS18, ten warheads.
0ne detonated, eight there.
That leaves one unaccounted for.
colonel Devoe,
there's somebody alive down here!
Hold on a minute. Take this.
Motherfuck!
God damn it!
We got a live one, colonel.
- Do you speak English?
- Yes, l went to Harvard.
Go, crimson!
Help me up, please.
- Where's the other warhead?
- Bring me up.
Listen.
You are gonna die unless you tell
me where the other warhead is.
- l don't know. He took it.
- Who?
l don't know his name.
He's with the ones who arranged this.
- kodoroff?
- No, he just handled the money.
it was the other one!
He made me dismantle the primary,
make it mobile.
- How?
- it's in his backpack.
Help me up, please?
(Soldier) Just hang on.
We'll bring you up.
kelly? A guy got away with a bomb.
'copy, Devoe.
All right, come on back.'
Got it. The bank account
on the kordech invoice.
Registered to an address in Grbavica,
a Serbian suburb of Sarajevo.
Good. Get this information to IF0R.
Tell them to proceed with caution.
Where are you going?
(Serbian) You made it.
l told you l would.
Is it heavy?
We must go.
- Are you all right?
- I've been better. How about you?
I've been better. We traced the money
to a man named Vlado Mirich.
lF0R found a tape in his apartment.
They're sending it to us now.
They say it has
a terrorist message on it.
colonel, the guy you caught
is Dr Amir Taraki.
Pakistani. PhD in astrophysics.
Educated at Harvard.
That's right. We educated
half the world's terrorists.
Tell me exactly what he said.
He took the primary from the warhead
and put it in a backpack.
The primary is full of plutonium.
it could take out ten city blocks
and kill 100,000 people in a densely
populated area like Sarajevo.
(Mirich) 'You will look at
what l have done and say,
'"0f course, why not?
They are all animals.
'"They have slaughtered
each other for centuries."
'But the truth is,
'l'm not a monster.
'I'm a human man.
'I'm just like you,
whether you like it or not.
'For years,
we have tried to live together
'until a war was waged on us.
'0n all of us.
'A war waged by our own leaders.
'And who supplied
the Serb cluster bombs,
'the croatian tanks,
'the Muslim artillery shells
'that killed our sons and daughters?
'it was the governments of the West
'who drew the boundaries
of our countries.
'Sometimes in ink,
sometimes in blood.
'The blood of our people.
'And now, you dispatch
your peacekeepers
'to write our destiny again.
'We can never accept this peace
that leaves us
'with nothing but pain.
'Pain the peacemakers
must be made to feel.
'Their wives, their children,
'their houses and churches.
'So now you know.
Now you must understand.
'Leave us to find our own destiny.
'May God have mercy on us all.'
lF0R can shut down Bosnia.
He'll never get into Sarajevo.
Wait, he's not going there.
We weren't meant to find this until
after he'd detonated the bomb.
"Pain the peacemakers
must be made to feel."
The peacemakers aren't in Bosnia.
They're in Europe and the US.
- They're signing a treaty this week.
- Tomorrow at the UN.
- What's the address?
- By the river, east side.
Forty-fourth Street, 44E.
He's goin' to New York.
What've you got?
We can only close the airport with
a Nuclear Emergency Response Plan.
- it has to come from her.
- I'll give it to her.
l wanted to know
who they were.
Secure line to NMcc.
This is Dr Julia kelly.
l am issuing a presidential directive
for a Federal Nuclear Emergency Plan.
We have a possible weapon
of mass destruction
coming into the United States by
unknown terrorist or terrorists.
- check in the rear.
- Yes, sir.
commencing diplomatic evacuation.
Ladies and gentlemen,
your attention please.
I'm with the UN. We've been informed
of a threat to the treaty signing.
We must get you off this plane
to ensure your safety.
lf you would all please stand up.
Thank you.
Move to the exits
at the rear and front of the aircraft
in orderly fashion.
- Glad you made it. coffee?
- No, thank you.
- l took a few Stay-Awakes earlier.
- Dr kelly?
- I'm fine.
- How many did she take?
This is Mark carey, Energy.
Here, Special Agent in charge,
David Branigan, FBI.
We're running NYPD and Agency
response from here
in co-ordination with D0E.
- Evacuation plans?
- National Guard.
- What about NEST?
- Energy has containment teams
on alert in Battery Park.
We're running casualty scenarios.
initial blast would throw 60 rads
of radiation out 3 miles.
That's most of lower Manhattan
and Queens.
2.5 to 3 million people,
50% survival rate.
Monitor wind patterns, and we need
radiation detectors, ground and air.
- lntel report from lF0R.
- Let me see that.
Vlado Mirich, Bosnian-Serb, radical.
Been missing for about a week.
Father fought with Tito.
Has a half-brother who was
a pianist in Sarajevo.
He's been arrested 3 times
for smuggling and black-marketeering.
- it's gotta be him.
- No, something's wrong.
The man in the tape. He's no black
marketeer and he's not a nationalist.
He said, "l am a Serb,
a croat and a Muslim".
He's holding everybody responsible.
The background doesn't fit.
I've got a V Mirich on SwissAir
Flight 1204 from Zurich to kennedy.
- Arriving when?
- 7 minutes ago.
call JFK. Send 'em a picture.
Excuse me!
cover all the exits.
Nobody gets out. Nobody!
- SwissAir, 1204, non-residents.
- Station 20.
(kelly) He's not here.
- He's not here!
- We got a possible lD at desk 7.
it's the far corner.
Excuse me.
Vlado Mirich?
Yes?
Who the hell is this?
All right.
Passport's fake.
Said he bought it in Sarajevo.
We've been able to detain eight men
with passports issued by countries
of the former Yugoslavia.
- None matches your description.
- Where the hell is he?
- Eight?
- Not including the delegations.
- What?
- They don't go through customs.
in all, must be a couple of hundred.
No, ma'am. We are talking
about a terrorist situation.
We need to detain
the entire delegation.
These are diplomats, guests of
the US. l can't order them around.
- Then l need names and room numbers.
- We're looking for Vlado Mirich.
This man isn't named Vlado Mirich.
This is Dusan Gavrich. He's with
the Bosnian-Serb delegation.
Their minister was assassinated
last week. He took his place.
The brother.
(Beeping)
Go!
0h, shit. Diplomatic papers.
They never even searched it.
Still warm.
Move.
(Gunshots and screaming)
Nina!
Help me!
Help me! Help my child!
Please help me!
(Speaks Serbian)
East 44th Street.
- D0E, got anything yet?
- choppers are up.
The backpack will be
leaking radiation
so we can locate him
within a 3 to 4 block area.
Set up roadblocks here.
We'll close off 2nd.
Funnel him down 43rd.
Deploy snipers between 1st and 2nd.
command centre.
General, we have to close down
the east side of Second Avenue
from 55th to 42nd and the north side
of 42nd from Sixth to the river.
(Devoe) 'We're gonna be
in position at the UN.
'instruct all field agents,
all snipers,
'subject cannot be aware
of the hunt.'
Something big at UN today.
Traffic bad all morning.
- (kelly) 'chopper 0ne, anything?'
- Negative.
'HQ, kelly. We're gonna work
our way south into the funnel.'
Suggest stopping anyone
with a backpack north of 55th.
Roger. How soon will
you get to the UN?
This is a national emergency.
- Get over here and spread 'em.
- Put your hands on your head!
Who are the fascists now, huh?
come on!
0k, guys, let's move it out.
come on. Let's move it.
- What the hell is this?
- We have instructions to...
it looks like Desert Storm!
Get these men outta here now!
- colonel.
- Yeah.
Where's the containment trucks?
- it's grid locked.
- Where are they?
There's a radiation source between
Third and Second, 54th and 46th.
- can you be more precise, D0E?
- 'Not at this altitude.'
keep an open channel. When we locate
him, go with the NEST team.
HRT command, put me direct
with your closest shooter.
- 'Hunter One, copy.'
- This is 0ne.
(Devoe)
'Expect he's comin' your way, 0ne.'
- (0ne) 'Do we have a green light?'
- (Devoe) 'Affirmative.'
(0fficer)
Get outside the barriers, folks.
l think he's between First
and Second, probably below 46th.
All positions, do you see target?
No, sir. Not me.
come on. come to Papa.
This is Four. Target acquired.
Three hundred metres.
Not clean. Too many friendlies.
- This is Leader. Take the shot.
- There's a child, a family.
Acknowledged. Take the shot.
Shoot him. come on.
Four, this is Leader.
l repeat, take the shot.
Take the shot!
Shoot him! Take the shot!
0h, God.
God damn it! Somebody shoot him!
This is 0ne. l have target acquired.
Four hundred yards, inbound.
No shot. Should open at 43rd.
FBI!
Take it easy, all right?
Just get outta here.
Dispatch, this is 1501.
l need backup on 43rd Street
as soon as you can get it for me.
Leader, this is 0ne.
Waiting for target to clear.
You with the backpack,
get your hands up.
Get your hands up!
I'm a diplomat
with the United Nations.
l must be allowed to pass.
Leader, I've lost him. He stopped.
- What?
- He went behind some trees.
He's gotta be there.
Reacquire. Move if you have to.
- What's in the backpack? cuffs.
- You got it.
- can you engage, One?
- Negative. Somebody shooting.
corner of 43rd and Second.
Is he down?
(0ne) 'Negative.
They're southbound, toward 42nd.'
Stay in contact with
the containment trucks
and have them ready
to move on my command.
- Where are you from?
- Philadelphia.
Give me the keys.
0ut of the way! D0E, you have him?
He's eastbound on 42nd.
Get out of the way!
Go!
- East of Second, off 41st.
- He went down there!
Stay behind me!
Drop your weapon,
and show me your fuckin' hands.
We got him. Alley off 41st.
(Yells)
- You all right?
- Yeah.
(Radio) 'The signal just quit.
He's gotta be indoors.'
0h, Vlado.
(Speaking Serbian)
(Door opens and bell rings)
Move!
- (Screaming)
- Move! Move!
Move!
- Anybody have him?
- (Radio) 'Negative. Nothing.'
- D0E, what have you got?
- 'Still picking up an energy source
'somewhere in the area.
We're circling back now.'
He'll never make it to the UN.
No need to.
He's got a nuclear weapon.
He just sits down behind a dumpster
and destroys half of Manhattan.
He doesn't wanna die
behind a dumpster.
He wants his death to mean something.
Fan out. We've got a new perimeter.
He's gotta be within 200 yards.
- Look for blood.
- There's no sign, colonel,
he probably ducked into a building.
- keep looking.
- 'We'll circle a six-block area.'
(choir singing)
Devoe!
Listen.
(Speaks Serbian)
(Shouts)
Go! Go!
(children screaming)
Father, take these children. Move it!
(Priest) come on, quickly, girls.
come on. Give me your hand.
Give me your hand.
Let's go.
Go, go, go, go.
You cannot stop this.
Never!
Ok.
0k, just...just stay still.
Stay there.
Stay still.
it's Ok.
You don't wanna die like this.
Tell me about the bomb.
Is it on the trigger?
Is it on a timer? Is it activated?
come on, talk to me.
We can decide on a way out of this.
No!
Who decided for my wife?
My child, murdered. Huh?
For what?
For breathing?
For smiling?
And now, l am left.
Who decides for me?
Mr Gavrich, what is it you want?
(Speaks Serbian)
l want it to be...
..like it was.
Sir, it's not our war.
- lt is now.
- No!
Son of a bitch.
Where the hell is NEST?
- it's on a timer.
- Listen, the bomb's on a timer.
ken, where the hell are they?
- l don't know.
- ken, tell me NEST is here.
'Affirmative.
They'll be there in four minutes.'
They're not gonna make it.
0k, you're gonna have to do this.
Understand?
Look at this, what do you see?
Take a look at this
and tell me what you see!
An SS18 primary with a plutonium
core. A bomb inside a bomb.
it has a capacitor-relay detonator,
double pull, double throw.
The only way of knowing
is to open it up.
What?
Let's move it into the chapel.
Get it off him. Get it off!
Hang on. We got a trip wire.
We'll move the man and the bomb.
All at once. Here we go. Ready? Go.
Let's go! careful!
Get the gate!
- Why in here?
- it'll help contain the radiation.
Get out of the church and evacuate
as many people as you can.
- l need something for the screws.
- Here.
- Anything. Quick!
- Go, go.
Devoe, get out of here.
0k, I'll be in the truck!
The plutonium core
is surrounded by explosive panels.
Uh, give me the knife.
l need the knife back.
lf we can separate one of the panels,
we may be able to blow up
the outer bomb without...
the core going to nuclear yield.
You're gonna blow this up.
You're gonna blow up the bomb?
You know what you're doin', right?
You've done this before?
Defused stolen nuclear primaries
jerry-rigged by Pakistanis?
No.
Ah, damn!
l need your gun.
Give me the gun, l need the gun.
Go.
Easy, easy, easy, easy!
it's all right.
(Devoe) 14...13...12... Let's go!
it won't move!
10...9...8...
come on! 7...6...5.
Go, go, go, go!
(Rapid beeping)
come here. Are you 0k?
Hey, are you Ok?
come here. come here.
come here, hey.
- You Ok?
- l think so.
Hey, listen, you're 0k.
All right?
Sir, we need you
to go with these medics.
Yeah, go. Go.
Julia, Julia!
Julia!
- So, they give you any new medals?
- Yes, they did.
- Well, you worked hard for them.
- Thank you.
We've got kind of a tradition
over at military ops.
Whenever combatants come back
from the field in one piece,
we buy each other a beer.
- You made that up.
- Yes, l did.
Well, um... l got ten more to go.
I'll wait.